代码审查是仔细系统的研究
Code review is careful systematic study
不是原始作者的源代码
of source code by somebody who is not the original author
密码的。
of the code.
有点像校对英文文本，
It's Kind of like proofreading English text,
就像学期论文一样。
like a term paper.
但是代码审查有两个目的。
But code review really has two purposes.
一是改进代码本身，
One is improving the code itself,
比如发现错误，或者预测
like finding bugs, or anticipating
以后可能出现的错误，或者检查它的清晰度，
bugs that might appear later, or checking its clarity,
或者检查与样式标准的一致性。
or checking for consistency with style standards.
但这也是为了提高程序员的水平。
But it's also about improving the programmer.
代码审查是程序员
Code review is an important way that programmers
互相学习和教导新的语言特点，
learn and teach each other about new language features,
关于项目设计或其编码的更改
about changes in design of the project or its coding
标准，关于新编程技术。
standards, about new programming techniques.
尤其是在开源项目中
In open source projects in particular
很多对话发生在代码评审的上下文中。
a lot of conversation happens in the context of code reviews.
代码评审在开源spot项目中广泛应用
Code review is widely practiced in open source spot projects
像Apache和Mozilla。
like Apache and Mozilla.
代码评审在工业中也得到了广泛的应用。
Code review is also widely practiced in industry.
例如，在Google，你不能推送任何代码
At Google, for example, you can't push any code
进入主仓库直到另一个工程师签字
into the main repository until another engineer has signed off
在代码评审中。
on it in a code review.
现在大多数公司和大型项目
Now most companies and large projects
有编码风格标准。
have coding style standards.
一个例子是Google风格的Java指南。
One example is the Google style guide for Java.
他们甚至可以得到相当详细的
They can get pretty detailed even
到指定空白的程度，您应该
to the point of specifying white space, how deep you should
缩进你的线，在哪里大括号
indent your lines, and where curly braces
括号应该在后面。
and parentheses should go.
有很多可能的变化。
There are many possible variations for that.
不幸的是，这些问题，
These kinds of questions, unfortunately,
经常导致神圣的战争。
often lead to holy wars.
因为它们最终会成为品味和风格的问题。
Because they end up being a matter of taste and style.
在6.005中，我们没有任何官方风格指南。
In 6.005, we don't have any official style guide.
我们不会告诉你花括号放在哪里。
We're not going to tell you where to put your curly braces.
这是你个人的决定。
That's a personal decision that you should make.
保持自我一致是很重要的
It's important to be self consistent, to always do it
你也一样。
the same way yourself.
但更重要的是
But it's even more important to follow
你正在做的项目的惯例。
the conventions of the project you're working on.
如果你是那种
If you're the kind of programmer who
重新设置每个模块的格式以符合您的个人风格，
reformats every module you touch to match your personal style,
你的队友会恨你的，没错。
your teammates are going to hate you, and rightly so.
你需要有团队精神。
You need to be a team player.
但有些规则是相当合理的
But there are some rules that are quite sensible
目标是我们三大酒店
and that target our big three properties
我们在最后一次阅读结束时谈到的
that we talked about at the end of the last reading
用比放大括号更有力的方式。
in a stronger way than just placing curly braces.
接下来的阅读将讨论
And the rest of this reading is going to talk about some
或者至少是那些
of these rules, or at least the ones
与课程中的这一点相关
that are relevant this point in the course
我们主要讨论的是编写基本Java。
where we're mostly talking about writing basic Java.
这是我们今天要讨论的规则的摘要。
Here's a summary of the rules we'll cover today.
不要重复你自己，经常被缩短为干燥。
Don't repeat yourself, often shortened to dry.
在你需要的地方写评论。
Write comments where you need them.
让你的代码快速失效。
Make your code fail fast.
避免使用魔法数字。
Avoid using magic numbers.
我们来说说什么是神奇数字。
And we'll say what magic numbers are.
每个变量都有一个目的。
Have one purpose for each variable.
对方法和变量使用好的名称。
Use good names for methods and variables.
不要使用全局变量。
Don't use global variables.
让你的方法返回结果，
Have your methods return their results,
而不是打印出来。
rather than printing them.
并使用空白来帮助读者阅读您的代码。
And use white space to help the reader read your code.
所以你应该
So these are some things you should
在代码检查时开始查找
start to look for when your code reviewing
本班其他同学
other students in this class and when
您正在查看自己的代码以进行改进。
you're looking at your own code for improvement.
不要认为这是一个详尽的清单。
Don't consider it an exhaustive list.
在这学期中我们将
Over the course of the semester we'll
谈论更多的事情，比如规格
talk about a lot more things like specifications
以及具有表示不变量的抽象数据类型，
and abstract data types with representation invariants,
并发性和线程安全性。
concurrency, and thread safety.
这些也将成为代码评审的素材。
And those will then become fodder for code review as well.
所以让我们从一个例子开始。
So let's start with an example.
这将是我们的第一个例子。
And this is going to be our first example.
我们叫它臭是因为程序员经常
And we call it smelly because programmers often
把糟糕的代码描述为
describe bad code as having a bad smell that
需要移除。
needs to be removed.
代码卫生是这个的积极版本。
Code hygiene is the positive version of this.
所以让我们从一些难闻的代码开始。
So let's start with some smelly code.
这是一个每年的方法日
Here is a method day of year that takes
三个整数参数，表示月、日
three integer parameters, representing the month, the day
一个月，一年。
of the month, and the year.
它应该在一年中的某一天
And it's supposed to return the day of the year
那个日期对应的。
that that date corresponds to.
这里是这个方法的主体。
And here is the body of this method.
接下来的几节和练习
Next few sections and the exercises
会挑出特殊的气味
are going to pick out the particular smells
在这段代码中。
in the body of this code here.
首先是不要重复你自己。
First one is don't repeat yourself.
重复的代码会给安全带来隐患。
Duplicated code is a risk to safety from bugs.
如果你在两个地方有相同或非常相似的代码，
If you have identical or very similar code in two places,
那么根本的风险在于
then the fundamental risk is that there
可能是两个副本中的错误。
may be a bug in both copies.
但是后来一些维修人员发现
But then some maintainer who discovers
那个错误并修复了它，只修复了一个
that bug and fixes it, fixes it in only one
但不是另一个。
place but not the other.
优秀的程序员以同样的方式避免重复代码
Good programmers avoid duplicated code in the same way
聪明的成年人不看就过马路。
that smart adults avoid crossing the street without looking.
编程时复制和粘贴
Copy and paste when you're programming
是一个非常诱人的工具。
is an enormously tempting tool.
但是你应该感到一种危险的感觉顺着你的脊柱往下跑
But you should feel a frisson of danger run down your spine
每次你用它。
every time you use it.
你复制的区块越长，风险就越大。
The longer the block you're copying is, the riskier it is.
所以不要重复你自己，或者开车，简而言之，
So don't repeat yourself, or drive, for short,
已经成为程序员的口头禅。
has become a programmer's mantra.
现在，一年中的这个例子充满了重复的代码。
Now this day of year example is full of repeated code.
你怎么把它弄干？
How would you dry it out?
让我们在下面的练习中看看。
Let's look at that in the exercises next.